thanard.kurutach@berkeley.edu

University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

750 Sutardja Dai Hall, Berkeley CA, 94720

2016 - present

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am interested in using artificial intelligence to help humans live better, and make better decisions. My current research goal is to develop algorithms that enable robots to efficiently solve complex decision-making problems using learning and planning.

EDUCATION

Candidate for Ph.D. in Computer Science Research Adivsors: Pieter Abbeel, Stuart Russell	4.0/4.0
Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA Candidate for B.S. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Candidate for B.S. in Mathematics	$\begin{array}{c} 2012 - 2016 \\ 4.9/5.0 \\ 5.0/5.0 \end{array}$
Awards and Honours	
UC Berkeley EECS Department Fellowship	2016
${\bf Provost's \ Graduate \ Excellence \ Fellowship} \ (\textit{decline})$	2016 - 2020
Lincoln Laboratory Undergraduate Research and Innovation Scholar	2015
Royal Thai Scholar	2011 - 2016
Round 2 Qualifier, Google Code Jam	2013
Gold Medal, 52nd International Mathematical Olympiad (IMO)	2011
Gold Medal, Asian Pacific Mathematics Olympiad (APMO)	2011
Silver Medal, 51st International Mathematical Olympiad (IMO)	2010
Silver Medal, 50th International Mathematical Olympiad (IMO)	2009

PUBLICATIONS

Angelina Wang, **Thanard Kurutach**, Kara Liu, Pieter Abbeel, Aviv Tamar. "Learning Robotic Manipulation through Visual Planning and Acting." *Proceedings of the Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)*, 2019.

Thanard Kurutach*, Aviv Tamar*, Ge Yang, Stuart Russell, Pieter Abbeel. "Learning Plannable Representation with Causal InfoGAN." *Proceedings of Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS)*, 2018

Thanard Kurutach, Ignasi Clavera, Yan Duan, Aviv Tamar, Pieter Abbeel. "Model Ensemble Trust Region Policy Optimization." *Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*, 2018.

Lawson Wong, **Thanard Kurutach**, Leslie Kaelbling, Tomás Lozano-Peréz. "Object-based World Modeling in Semi-Static Environments with Dependent Dirichlet-Process Mixtures." *Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2016.

ORAL PRESENTATIONS

Learning Representation for Planning and Acting. BayLearn, Facebook. October 2018.

Learning Plannable Representation with Causal InfoGAN. ICML/IJCAI/AAMAS Workshop on Planning and Learning. July 2018.

RESEARCH AND INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Berkeley Artificial Intelligence Research (BAIR), Research Assistant	2016 - present
Google, Inc., Speech Team, Research Intern	2016
EnergySage, Inc., Data Scientist Intern	2016
Learning and Intelligent Systems Group, with Kaelbling, Lozano-Peréz	2014-2016
MIT CSAIL Machine Learning Group, with Stefanie Jegelka	2015 - 2015
National ICT Australia, Research Intern	2014
Harvard Microrobotics Laboratory, with Robert J. Wood	2013
Nanostructures and Computation Group, with Steven G. Johnson	2012 - 2013

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Lecture AI and Neural Network Design, Leading Trends in Humanities, the Sciences and Technology, UC Berkeley Extension

Department of EECS, UC Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

Graduate Student Instructor

• CS188: Introduction to Artificial Intelligence, Fall 2018.

Department of EECS, MIT, Cambridge, MA

Teaching Assistant

- 6.036: Introduction to Machine Learning, Spring 2016
- 6.008: Introduction to Inference, Fall 2015

Lab Assistant

• 6.001: Introduction to EECS, Spring 2013

Department of Mathematics, MIT, Cambridge, MA

Writing Coach

• 18.310: Principles of Applied Mathematics, Fall 2014

MENTORING AND ADVISING

Undergraduate students:

Fenglu Hong, UC Berkeley

Yilin Wu, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Wilson Yan, UC Berkeley

Angelina Wang, UC Berkeley

Kara Liu, UC Berkeley

Christine Tung, UC Berkeley

Visiting Scholars:

Ge Yang, PhD student, University of Chicago

Misha Laskin, PhD graduate, University of Chicago

Yuto Fujii, Engineer, Komatsu Ltd

COMPUTATIONAL SKILLS

Python, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Matlab, Java, C/C++, L*TFX, HTML5/CSS, Javascript, jQuery, etc.